Peter Lyons

1064 Adams Ave, Louisville, CO 80027

pete@peterlyons.com

http://peterlyons.com

(720) 213-6412

Web Developer (Full Stack)

Veteran software craftsman with deep technical experience and a passion for thoughtful, well-constructed software. I can build sophisticated web applications from the ground up including cloud based server provisioning, OS configuration, database systems, application servers, web server configuration, and security. I care about user experience and strive toward simple software that is a joy to use. I am dedicated to simplicity and pragmatism.

Skills

Web Development JavaScript, CoffeeScript, node.js, ExpressJS, Backbone.js, Mocha.js, Ruby on Rails,

jQuery, AJAX, HTML, CSS, Fabric, git, Mac OS X, nginx, Apache, PostgreSQL,

MongoDB, MySQL

Enterprise Software Python, Java, SQL, Subversion, Clearcase

Systems Administration | Bourne Shell, Linux, Solaris, Windows, TCP/IP, Troubleshooting

Experience

Peter Lyons LLC, Louisville, CO (www.peterlyons.com)

February 2011-Present

- Independent Web Developer
 - Freelance web development specializing in custom applications
 - Ruby on Rails application development with **Dojo4** agency building RESTful JSON APIs for mobile web applications

Social Communications Company, Mountain View, CA (<u>www.sococo.com</u>) Web Developer

February 2012-Present

- Developed rich Internet application web application for the Sococo Team Space Product on a Backbone.js, jQuery, PHP technology stack
- Built automated build & deployment system on top of Fabric framework
- Guided project toward technical best practices including test driven development, automated deployment, and code modularization

Hewlett-Packard, Cupertino, CA (www.hp.com) **Software Design VI**

November 2007-January 2011

- Led a large team to a successful re-architecture of the OS provisioning feature slashing technical debt, reducing complexity, and providing an easier-to-use and more powerful feature with six times *less* code
- Designed and implemented a best-in-class Solaris Patching feature based on my own professional services work while consulting at Opsware customers
- Development lead for OS Provisioning and Solaris Patching features on the HP Server Automation product across multiple releases
- Maintained and improved a large, mature, and complex code base. This includes making careful trade-off decisions around product functionality, defect management, and quickly resolving top-priority customer escalations
- Note Opsware was acquired by HP in November 2007 for \$1.6 billion

Opsware, New York, NY (www.opsware.com)

Senior Consulting Engineer

August 2004-November 2007

 Technical lead for the Eastern US, providing best practices, guidance, procedures, and support to less experienced team members

- Developed enhancements to meet the needs of large financial services clients. Enhanced Opsware's Solaris
 Patching capabilities for deeper automation. Created program to synchronize user accounts with an external LDAP
 directory. Developed new web GUIs for customer-specific enhancements.
- Worked closely with customers to design, plan, and implement Opsware Server Automation System to automate management of complex, large-scale, heterogeneous, enterprise data centers
- · Provided troubleshooting, analysis, and technical expertise in high-pressure, escalated production problems
- Successfully upgraded nearly every Opsware customer in the Eastern US. Used precision and careful, thorough planning to turn nightmare, disaster-prone on-site product upgrades into successes.

Accenture, New Providence, NJ (www.accenture.com) Senior Programmer

November 2002-August 2004

- Responsible for planning, design, implementation, and operation of multiple carrier-class highly-available
 computer networks involving dozens of servers, layer 2 and 3 network switches and routers, fiber channel SAN
 systems, firewalls, load balancers, SSL accelerators, and tape backup
- Designed and implemented enterprise-class software solutions using Microsoft Active Directory, DNS, Exchange Server, Microsoft Operations Manager, IIS, SQL Server, ISA Server, Commerce Server
- Developed an end user self-provisioning portal for a Hosted Exchange solution including database schema design, T-SQL stored procedures, object-oriented business logic classes, an abstract reusable superclass for persistent business objects, transaction processing across multiple databases, LDAP directories, and web services, a robust exception handling and logging system, and web presentation layer in ASP.NET
- Served as key resource in troubleshooting and resolving difficult problems in both functionality and performance in heterogeneous network environments
- Quickly learned a vast array of cutting edge hardware and software technology from a wide range of vendors

CodeFab, Inc., New York, NY (www.codefab.com)

Software Engineer

August 2001 - September 2002

- Developed and maintained numerous sophisticated database driven web applications including a real-time trading system
- Integrated diverse technologies such as email (JavaMail), LDAP directories (JNDI), XML-RPC, and WebDAV
- Created transparent, on-the-fly database upgrade system that significantly reduced the downtime, risk and complexity of updating production software
- Designed, developed, and integrated centralized, single sign-on authentication system that allowed employees to use multiple web applications without needing to reauthenticate
- Maintained internal and external company web sites; redesigned and updated external web site for better standards compliance, browser compatibility and easier access to current information
- Created simple content management system to facilitate updating news section of the web site

Education

Oberlin College, Oberlin, OH

Bachelor of Music in Saxophone Performance, GPA 3.98

May 2001

• Courses in Object-Oriented Programming, Databases, Networking, and Computer Organization

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Music, saxophone, aerial fabric, rock climbing, mountain biking, hiking, skiing